[
  {
    "id": "1",
    "question": "Which Nigerian rapper is known as 'Mr. Incredible'?",
    "options": [
      "Phyno",
      "Ice Prince",
      "M.I Abaga",
      "Vector"
    ],
    "answer": "M.I Abaga",
    "category": "Music"
  },
  {
    "id": "2",
    "question": "Who is known as the 'Queen of Afrobeat'?",
    "options": [
      "Tiwa Savage",
      "Yemi Alade",
      "Asa",
      "Simi"
    ],
    "answer": "Tiwa Savage",
    "category": "Music"
  },
  {
    "id": "3",
    "question": "Which food is Enugu popularly known for?",
    "options": [
      "Okpa",
      "Suya",
      "Chin Chin",
      "Kuli Kuli"
    ],
    "answer": "Okpa",
    "category": "Food"
  },
  {
    "id": "5",
    "question": "Which Nigerian won the Olympic gold medal in long jump?",
    "options": [
      "Blessing Okagbare",
      "Chioma Ajunwa",
      "Mary Onyali",
      "Falilat Ogunkoya"
    ],
    "answer": "Chioma Ajunwa",
    "category": "Sports"
  },
  {
    "id": "6",
    "question": "Which year did Nigeria win the Olympic football gold?",
    "options": [
      "1996",
      "2000",
      "1992",
      "1988"
    ],
    "answer": "1996",
    "category": "Sports"
  },
  {
    "id": "7",
    "question": "Who was Nigeria\u2019s first president?",
    "options": [
      "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
      "Obafemi Awolowo",
      "Yakubu Gowon",
      "Ahmadu Bello"
    ],
    "answer": "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
    "category": "9ja History"
  },
  {
    "id": "8",
    "question": "In what year did Nigeria gain independence?",
    "options": [
      "1960",
      "1956",
      "1970",
      "1963"
    ],
    "answer": "1960",
    "category": "9ja History"
  },
  {
    "id": "9",
    "question": "What's the title of Wizkid's first album?",
    "options": [
      "Superstar",
      "Made in Lagos",
      "Ayo",
      "Sounds from the Other Side"
    ],
    "answer": "Superstar",
    "category": "Music"
  },
  {
    "id": "10",
    "question": "Which river is the longest in Nigeria?",
    "options": [
      "Niger River",
      "Benue River",
      "Osun River",
      "Cross River"
    ],
    "answer": "Niger River",
    "category": "9ja History"
  },
  {
    "id": "11",
    "question": "What is the official currency of Nigeria?",
    "options": [
      "Naira",
      "Dollar",
      "Pound",
      "Euro"
    ],
    "answer": "Naira",
    "category": "9ja History"
  },
  {
    "id": "12",
    "question": "Which festival is celebrated in Nigeria to mark the end of Ramadan?",
    "options": [
      "Eid-el-Fitr",
      "Eid-el-Adha",
      "Christmas",
      "New Year"
    ],
    "answer": "Eid-el-Fitr",
    "category": "9ja History"
  },
  {
    "id": "13",
    "question": "What is the most popular sport in Nigeria?",
    "options": [
      "Football",
      "Basketball",
      "Cricket",
      "Tennis"
    ],
    "answer": "Football",
    "category": "9ja History"
  },
  {
    "id": "14",
    "question": "Which Nigerian city is known as the 'Centre of Excellence'?",
    "options": [
      "Lagos",
      "Abuja",
      "Port Harcourt",
      "Ibadan"
    ],
    "answer": "Lagos",
    "category": "9ja History"
  },
  {
    "id": "15",
    "question": "Which song made Burna Boy win his first Grammy?",
    "options": [
      "Ye",
      "Last Last",
      "Twicwe as Tall",
      "Anybody"
    ],
    "answer": "Twicwe as Tall",
    "category": "Music"
    },
    {
    "id": "16",
    "question": "Which Nigerian artist is known for the song 'Dumebi'?",
    "options": [
      "Rema",
      "Omah Lay",
      "Joeboy",
      "Fireboy DML"
    ],
    "answer": "Rema",
    "category": "Music"
    },
    {
    "id": "17",
    "question": "Which artist is known as “African Giant”?",
    "options": [
        "Davido", 
        "Burna",
        "Wizkid",
        "Olamide"
    ],
    "answer": "Burna",
    "category": "Music"
    },
    {
    "id": "18",
    "question": "Which song is known for the line “Now wey I dey alive” by Patoranking?",
    "options": [
        "No Kissing",
        "Abule",
        "Alubarika",
        "Celebrate Me"
    ],
    "answer": "Celebrate Me",
    "category": "Music"
    },
    {
    "id": "19",
    "question": "Who featured on Wizkid's “Essence”?",
    "options": [
        "Tems",
        "Tiwa Savage",
        "Burna Boy",
        "Omah Lay"
    ],  
    "answer": "Tems",
    "category": "Music"
    },
    {
    "id": "20",
    "question": "What is the title of Davido's debut album?",
    "options": [
        "Omo Baba Olowo",
        "A Better Time",
        "Son of Mercy",
        "A Good Time"
    ],  
    "answer": "Omo Baba Olowo",
    "category": "Music"
    },  
    {
    "id": "21",
    "question": "What is the main ingredient in Moi Moi?",
    "options": [
        "Beans",
        "Rice",
        "Yam",
        "Plantain"
    ],  
    "answer": "Beans",
    "category": "Food"
    },
    {
    "id": "22",
    "question": "Which Nigerian dish is made from fermented locust beans?", 
    "options": [
        "Ogiri",
        "Iyan",
        "Efo Riro",
        "Pepper Soup"
    ],
    "answer": "Ogiri",
    "category": "Food"
    },
    { 
    "id": "23",
    "question": "Which of these is not a type of Nigerian soup?",
    "options": [
        "Egusi",
        "Ogbono",
        "Bitterleaf",
        "Jollof"
    ],  
    "answer": "Jollof",
    "category": "Food"
    },
    {   
    "id": "24",
    "question": "Which of these spices is common in Jollof Rice?",
    "options": [
        "Thyme",
        "Curry",
        "Ginger",
        "Garlic"
    ],
    "answer": "Thyme",
    "category": "Food"
    },
    {
    "id": "25",
    "question": "Which of these is a popular Yoruba dish?",
    "options": [
        "Afang Soup",
        "Efo Riro",
        "Okpa",
        "Ofe Nsala"
    ],  
    "answer": "Efo Riro",
    "category": "Food"
    },
    {
    "id": "26",
    "question": "What is the main ingredient in Akara?",
    "options": [
        "Beans",
        "Cassava",
        "Yam",
        "Plantain"
    ],  
    "answer": "Beans",
    "category": "Food"
    },
    {
    "id": "27",
    "question": "What is a common street food in Lagos known as “Boli”?",
    "options": [
        "Roasted Plantain",
        "Fried Yam",
        "Puff Puff",
        "Grilled Fish"
    ],
    "answer": "Roasted Plantain",
    "category": "Food"
    },
    {
    "id": "28",
    "question": "Which Nigerian dish is made from pounded yam?",
    "options": [
        "Iyan",
        "Eba",
        "Fufu",
        "Pounded Cassava"
    ],
    "answer": "Iyan",
    "category": "Food"
    },
    {
    "id": "29",
    "question": "Which soup is famous among the Efik people?",
    "options": [
        "Afang Soup",
        "Egusi Soup",
        "Ogbono Soup",
        "Bitterleaf Soup"
    ],  
    "answer": "Afang Soup",
    "category": "Food"
    },
    {
    "id": "30",
    "question": "Who was Nigeria's first Prime Minister?",
    "options": [
      "Nnamdi Azikiwe",
      "Abubakar Tafawa Balewa",
      "Obafemi Awolowo",
      "Ahmadu Bello"
    ],  
    "answer": "Abubakar Tafawa Balewa",
    "category": "9ja History"
    },
    {
    "id": "31",
    "question": "What is the traditional attire of the Yoruba called?",
    "options": [
      "Buba and Iro",
      "Kaftan",
      "Agbada",
      "Isi Agu"
    ],
    "answer": "Buba and Iro",
    "category": "9ja History"
    },
    {
    "id": "32",
    "question": "Which Nigerian state is known as the 'Home of Peace'?",    
    "options": [
      "Benue",
      "Bauchi",
      "Kano",
      "Kaduna"
    ],  
    "answer": "Benue",
    "category": "9ja History"
    },
    {
    "id": "33",
    "question": "Which Nigerian city is known for its oil production?",
    "options": [
      "Port Harcourt",
      "Lagos",
      "Abuja",
      "Calabar"
    ],  
    "answer": "Port Harcourt",
    "category": "9ja History"
    },
    {
    "id": "34",
    "question": "What is the capital of Cross River State?",
    "options": [
      "Calabar",
      "Uyo",
      "Port Harcourt",
      "Enugu"
    ],  
    "answer": "Calabar",
    "category": "9ja History"
    },
    {
    "id": "35", 
    "question": "Which year did Nigeria become a republic?",
    "options": [
      "1963",
      "1960",
      "1970",
      "1980"
    ],  
    "answer": "1963",
    "category": "9ja History"
    },
    {
    "id": "36",
    "question": "Who was Nigeria's first military Head of State?",
    "options": [
      "Yakubu Gowon",
      "Muhammadu Buhari",
      "Sani Abacha",
      "Johnson Aguiyi-Ironsi"
    ],
    "answer": "Johnson Aguiyi-Ironsi",
    "category": "9ja History"
    },
    {
    "id": "37",
    "question": "Which Nigerian city is known as the “Coal City”?",
    "options": [
      "Enugu",
      "Jos",
      "Lagos",
      "Ibadan"
    ],
    "answer": "Enugu",
    "category": "9ja History"
    },
    {
    "id": "38",
    "question": "The famous “Olojo Festival” is celebrated in which state?",
    "options": [
      "Osun",
      "Ekiti",
      "Oyo",
      "Lagos"
    ],
    "answer": "Osun",
    "category": "9ja History"
    },
    {
    "id": "39",
    "question": "Which Nigerian state is known for the 'Argungu Festival'?",
    "options": [
      "Kebbi",
      "Kano",
      "Sokoto",
      "Yobe"
    ],  
    "answer": "Kebbi",
    "category": "9ja History"
    },
    {
    "id": "40",
    "question": "Who is known as the “Mathematical” in Nigerian football history?",
    "options": [
      "Jay Jay Okocha",
      "Nwankwo Kanu",
      "Rashidi Yekini",
      "Segun Odegbami"
    ],
    "answer": "Segun Odegbami",
    "category": "Sports"
    },
    {
    "id": "41",
    "question": "Which Nigerian football club is known as 'The People's Elephant'?",
    "options": [
      "Enyimba FC",
      "Rangers International",
      "Kano Pillars",
      "Shooting Stars"
    ],  
    "answer": "Enyimba FC",
    "category": "Sports"
    },
    {
    "id": "42",
    "question": "Which Nigerian athlete is known for the 100m sprint?",
    "options": [
      "Olusoji Fasuba",
      "Mary Onyali",
      "Blessing Okagbare",
      "Tobi Amusan"
    ],
    "answer": "Olusoji Fasuba",
    "category": "Sports"
    },
    {
    "id": "43",
    "question": "Which Nigerian footballer is known as 'The Lion of Africa'?",
    "options": [
      "Samuel Eto'o",
      "Yaya Toure",
      "Didier Drogba",
      "Nwankwo Kanu"
    ],  
    "answer": "Nwankwo Kanu",
    "category": "Sports"
    },
    {
    "id": "44",
    "question": "Which Nigerian football club has the most league titles?",
    "options": [
      "Enyimba FC",
      "Rangers International",
      "Kano Pillars",
      "Shooting Stars"
    ],
    "answer": "Enyimba FC",
    "category": "Sports"
    },
    {
    "id": "45",
    "question": "Which Nigerian athlete is known for the 400m hurdles?",
    "options": [
      "Tobi Amusan",
      "Blessing Okagbare",
      "Mary Onyali",
      "Olusoji Fasuba"
    ],
    "answer": "Tobi Amusan",
    "category": "Sports"
    },
    {
    "id": "46",
    "question": "Which Nigerian female athlete is known as the “Queen of the Track”?",
    "options": [
      "Blessing Okagbare",
      "Mary Onyali",
      "Falilat Ogunkoya",
      "Chioma Ajunwa"
    ],
    "answer": "Blessing Okagbare",
    "category": "Sports"
    },
    {
    "id": "47",
    "question": "Who is Nigeria's first Olympic gold medalist?",
    "options": [
      "Chioma Ajunwa",
      "Mary Onyali",
      "Falilat Ogunkoya",
      "Blessing Okagbare"
    ],
    "answer": "Chioma Ajunwa",
    "category": "Sports"
    },
    {
    "id": "48",
    "question": "Who was the captain of the Super Eagles during the 2013 AFCON win?",
    "options": [
      "Joseph Yobo",
      "Vincent Enyeama",
      "John Obi Mikel",
      "Obafemi Martins"
    ],  
    "answer": "Joseph Yobo",
    "category": "Sports"
    },
    {
    "id": "49",
    "question": "Which Nigerian player has won the UEFA Champions League?",
    "options": [
      "Samuel Eto'o",
      "Jay Jay Okocha",
      "Nwankwo Kanu",
      "Vincent Enyeama"
    ],
    "answer": "Nwankwo Kanu",
    "category": "Sports"
    },
    {
    "id": "50",
    "question": "Who is the first Nigerian boxer to become a heavyweight world champion?",
    "options": [
      "Samuel Peter",
      "Anthony Joshua",
      "David Haye",
      "Bola Ahmed Tinubu"
    ],
    "answer": "Samuel Peter",
    "category": "Sports"
    },
    {
    "id": "51",
    "question": "Who is the first Nigerian to win a UFC title?",
    "options": [
      "Kamaru Usman",
      "Israel Adesanya",
      "Anthony Joshua",
      "Sodiq Yusuff"
    ],
    "answer": "Kamaru Usman",
    "category": "Sports"
    },
    {
    "id": "52",
    "question": "Who holds the Nigerian record for men's 100m?",
    "options": [
      "Olusoji Fasuba",
      "Divine Oduduru",
      "Seye Ogunlewe",
      "Francis Obikwelu"
    ],
    "answer": "Olusoji Fasuba",
    "category": "Sports"
    },
    {   
    "id": "53",
    "question": "Which Nigerian athlete is known as “The Beast” in boxing?",
    "options": [
      "Anthony Joshua",
      "Samuel Peter",
      "David Haye",
      "Kamaru Usman"
    ],
    "answer": "Samuel Peter",
    "category": "Sports"
    },
    {
    "id": "54",
    "question": "Which Nigerian goalkeeper is famous for his penalty saves?",
    "options": [
      "Vincent Enyeama",
      "Peter Rufai",
      "Ikechukwu Ezenwa",
      "Dele Alampasu"
    ],
    "answer": "Vincent Enyeama",
    "category": "Sports"
    },
    {
    "id": "55",
    "question": "Which Nigerian player won the FIFA U-17 World Cup Golden Boot in 2015?",
    "options": [
      "Victor Osimhen",
      "Kelechi Iheanacho",
      "Samuel Chukwueze",
      "Moses Simon"
    ],
    "answer": "Victor Osimhen",
    "category": "Sports"
    }
]